Guide to the Shailer Mathews Papers 1892-1942
University of Chicago Library
Mathews, Shailer. Papers
1892-1942
22 linear feet (44 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
Shailer Mathews (1863-1941) Professor, 1894-1933, Dean of the Divinity School, 1908-1933. Contains correspondence, minutes, articles, reports, and teaching materials. Subjects relate to the history of the University of Chicago and the Divinity School, the development of the religious and social ideas known as Modernism, and the Chautauqua Institute.
Information on Use
Access
No restrictions.
Biographical Note
Shailer Mathews was born in Portland, Maine on May 26, 1863. He received an A.B. from Colby College in 1884, and an M.A. in 1887 In the latter year, he also graduated from Newton Theological Seminary, after which he spent a number of years as a professor at Colby. He was on leave during the year 1890-1891, studying at the University of Berlin, and returned with an enthusiasm for research and the historical-scientific approach to all knowledge that became a life-long characteristic.
In 1894, at the invitation of William Rainey Harper, he came to the newly reorganized University of Chicago, where he was to play an influential role until his retirement in 1933. He held a number of positions in the Divinity School of the University; Assistant Professor of New Testament Interpretation, 1894-97; Professor in the same field, 1897-1905; Professor of Systematic Theology, 1905-1906; Professor of Historical and Comparative Theology, 1906-1933; junior Dean, 1899-1908; Dean, 1908-1933. At the same time he played a very active part as a member of the administrative council of the University as a whole and as a participant in countless faculty and administrative activities He found time to write or to edit more than a score of books, many of which were extremely influential and widely read, particularly those dealing with the new approach to religious knowledge then widely disparaged as "Modernism" and with the social application of the Christian Gospel. He edited a journal of general observation and comment on world affairs, "The World Today", from 1903 to 1911; he also was editor of "The Biblical World", 1913-20 For a long period he was an editorial adviser on religious books for Harpers
Dr. Mathews did not believe that real scholarship could prosper in an "ivory-tower" and he was always active in a great variety of organizations and associations outside the University. He was a member of the Chicago Co-operative Council of City Missions (the forerunner of the Council of Churches), 1908-1915; of the Chicago Baptist Executive Council, 1910-1919; and of many other similar groups. His abilities as a leader and parliamentary officer were drawn upon in many ways within these groups He was the first president of the Federal Council of Churches, 1912-1916, and had much to do with the formulation of its policies and procedures. In 1915 he served at a very critical juncture as president of the Northern Baptist Convention and is credited with being largely responsible for saving that body from splitting in two over the question of Modernism versus Fundamentalism. From 1929 to 1932 he was president of the Chicago Church Federation.
The breadth of Mathews' interests is indicated by his association with a number of other activities not officially related to the churches or directly to theology. He was, for example, director of religious work for the Chautauqua Institute from 1912-1934, most of which time he was also a trustee of the association and a major figure in Chautauqua's development. In 1920 he served as a member of the Kobe College Foundation and made a trip to Japan which made him a national spokesman for Japanese and American friendship. His interest in politics and social welfare is indicated by his membership on the board of trustees of the Church Peace Union in 1914, as well as his participation and encouragement in the work of Jane Addams' Hull House. However, he strongly supported the cause of the Allies once the United States entered the first World War and from 1917 to 1918 served at the appointment of Illinois' governor as State Director of War Savings. He co-operated and supported progressive movements in politics led by men like Charles Merriam in Chicago and Theodore Roosevelt on the national scene.
Mathews died on October 23, 1941.
Scope Note
During the year 1954-55, these records were removed from storage in the basement of Swift Hall and deposited in the University Archives Their present organization is based on the arrangement at the time of transfer and in general reflects their original arrangement as working files The many relationships of the School and of Shailer Mathews with other organizations are not easily discernable in the present basic chronological arrangement but it should be noted that symbols have been introduced in this guide to indicate the dominant subject matter in otherwise general folders However, these symbols should be used with caution since they are not to be understood as being inclusive of all the correspondence that might exist in a particular folder. Also, the dating assigned to each folder is not necessarily inclusive but should serve as a suggestion to the general location of specific material
Following deposit in the Archives some general weeding was performed on the papers which was limited to a vast amount of routine matters Occasional samplings of this routine correspondence and memoranda were saved and are so marked in the guide below.
The sketch of Mathews' career has been appended to assist users of this collection to gain a minimal understanding of the scope of his varied activities as a University administrator, scholar, and churchman. His autobiography, New Faith for Old (New York, Macmillan, 1936) should be also consulted.
Dr. Mathews' papers in the possession of the University Archives are to a large extent administrative records dealing with matters affecting both the Divinity School and the University as a whole. There is also considerable correspondence touching upon the practical matters of American church life, particularly the efforts of the strict fundamentalists to split the churches over the modernism issue; a large group of papers bears upon the development of the Chautaugua Institute, particularly its religious program; and the collection includes miscellaneous correspondence, lecture notes, and manuscripts of published and unpublished articles and books There are no examples of correspondence with leading political figures, but many, of course, of correspondence with educational and religious leaders
The chief emphases of Dr. Mathews papers will be found in three areas, 1) the history of the University of Chicago and of the Divinity School; 2) the history of the development of the religious and social ideas which came to be known as "Modernism" and of the struggles within Protestantism which resulted from them; and 3) the reconstruction of the general intellectual, social, and spiritual climate which characterized the great era of vast changes in American life from 1890-1930 In addition valuable material on the history of Chautaugua and of a number of other movements and groups is scattered through the whole. The attitude of religious leaders toward the first World War is another example of a secondary topic upon which Dr. Mathews' papers shed some interesting light.
Related Resources
The following related resources are located in the Department of Special Collections:
http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/spcl/select.html
Subject Headings
Mathews, Shailer, 1863-1941; Chautauqua Institution; University of Chicago -- History; University of Chicago. Divinity School
INVENTORY
- Divinity School, Historical material (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Divinity School, Historical material (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Divinity School, Historical material (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Divinity School, Historical material (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Divinity School, Historical material (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Shailer Mathews, Articles and lectures (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Shailer Mathews, Articles and lectures (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Shailer Mathews, Articles and lectures (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Shailer Mathews?, Articles (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Shailer Mathews?, Course notes (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Shailer Mathews?, Course notes (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Shailer Mathews?, Course notes (possibly Gerald B. Smith's notes, not Mathews) (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Shailer Mathews?, Course notes (possibly Gerald B. Smith's notes, not Mathews) (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Divinity School, Faculty minutes, 1892-1907 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Divinity School, Faculty minutes, 1908-1914 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Divinity School, Faculty minutes, 1915-1921 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Divinity School, Faculty minutes, 1922-1933 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Divinity School, Photographs of the first graduating class and the last of Morgan Park Academy, 1892-1893 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Shailer Mathews/Divinity School, 1897-1911 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Shailer Mathews/Divinity School, 1897-1911 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Northwestern Baptist Educational Society, 1895-1921 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- E. B. Hubert, P-Z, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Morgan Park, South Side and Bradley. Board of Trustees minutes, 1898-1900 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Morgan Park, South Side and Bradley. Board of Trustees minutes, 1900-1901 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Shailer Mathews/Personal Correspondence, June-December, 1899 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence/Personal Correspondence, 1899-1912 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence/Personal Correspondence, 1899-1912 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence/Personal Correspondence, 1899-1912 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence/Personal Correspondence, 1899-1912 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence, July-December, 1900 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence, A-B, to December, 1900 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence, G-I, to December, 1900 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence, M-P, to December, 1900 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence, R-S, to December, 1900 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Shailer Mathews/P, January-June, 1900 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Shailer Mathews/P, June-December, 1900 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence, 1900-1911 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence, 1900-1911 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Divinity School, Faculty, mostly 1900-1903 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence, January-July, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence, July, 1901-July, 1902 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence, July, 1902-June, 1903 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence, A-B, to June, 1903 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence, C-D, to June, 1903 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence, E-G, to June, 1903 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence, H-I, to June, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence, J-L, to June, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence, M-O, to June, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence, P-R, to June, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence, S-Z, to June, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- E. D. Burton and W. A. Stevens correspondence on the Harmony of the Gospels, mostly 1903-1906 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- E. D. Burton and W. A. Stevens correspondence on the Harmony of the Gospels, mostly 1903-1906 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- E. D. Burton and W. A. Stevens correspondence on the Harmony of the Gospels, mostly 1903-1906 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence, July, 1903-January, 1905 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Baptist Advisory Committee of the Theological Union, Committee of One Hundred, 1904-1906 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Baptist Advisory Committee of the Theological Union, Committee of One Hundred, 1904-1906 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Baptist Advisory Committee of the Theological Union, Committee of One Hundred, 1904-1906 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Baptist Theological Faculties Union, 1904-1908 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Baptist Theological Faculties Union, 1904-1908 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Baptist Theological Faculties Union, 1904-1908 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Baptist Theological Faculties Union, 1904-1908 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence, A-B, to August, 1905 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence, C-D, to August, 1905 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence, H-I, to August, 1905 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence, J-O, to August, 1905 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence, P-Z, to August, 1905 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Shailer Mathews/Personal Correspondence, January, 1905-April, 1907 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Shailer Mathews/Personal Correspondence, April, 1906, 1907 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Shailer Mathews, Course outlines and bibliographies, 1907 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Shailer Mathews, Course outlines and bibliographies, 1907 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence, 1907-1908 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence, A-D, to May, 1908 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence, E-I, to May, 1908 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Shailer Mathews/G, J-L, to May, 1908 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence, M-O, to May, 1908 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence, P-S, to May, 1908 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence, T-Z, to May, 1908 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Shailer Mathews/Personal Correspondence, 1908 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence, A-B, May, 1908-September, 1909 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence C-D, May, 1908-September, 1909 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence H-I, May, 1908-September, 1909 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence M-O, May, 1908-September, 1909 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence P-R, May, 1908-September, 1909 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence S-Z, May, 1908-September, 1909 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Shailer Mathews/Chautaugua Institute, 1908-1915 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Shailer Mathews/Chautaugua Institute, 1908-1915 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Shailer Mathews/Chautaugua Institute, 1908-1915 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Shailer Mathews/Personal Correspondence, January-September, 1909 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Baptist Theological Union, 1909 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Divinity School, 1909-1911 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Northern Baptist Convention, Social Service Commission, 1909-1913 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence Mc and U-V, 1910-1911 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Divinity School, Christian Union, 1910-1916 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence A-B, to October, 1911 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence C-I, to October, 1911 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence J-L, to October, 1911 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence M-Z, to October, 1911 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Shailer Mathews/Personal Correspondence, February-October, 1911 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Shailer Mathews/Personal Correspondence, October-December, 1911 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Shailer Mathews/Baptist Executive Committee, 1912-1919 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Shailer Mathews/Baptist Executive Committee, 1912-1919 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence 1913-1923 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence 1913-1923 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence 1913-1923 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence 1913-1923 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Shailer Mathews/G/Personal Correspondence, 1913-1924 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Shailer Mathews/G/Personal Correspondence, 1913-1924 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Shailer Mathews/G/Personal Correspondence, 1913-1924 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence 1914-1921 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence 1914-1921 (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Shailer Mathews/Personal Correspondence, 1914-1924 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Divinity School/Shailer Mathews/G, to July 1915 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Divinity School/Shailer Mathews/G, to July 1915 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Divinity School/Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence 1915-1916 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Divinity School/Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence 1915-1916 (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Divinity School/Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence 1915-1916 (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Divinity School, "Active students" file, 1915-1916 (retained as sample) (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Shailer Mathews/Chautaugua Institute, 1915-1917 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Shailer Mathews/Chautaugua Institute, 1915-1917 (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Shailer Mathews/Chautaugua Institute, 1915-1917 (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Co-operative Council of City Missions of Chicago, 1915-1917 (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Northern Baptist Convention, Minutes, 1915-1919 (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Northern Baptist Convention, Minutes, 1915-1919 (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Northern Baptist Convention, Five Year Program Minutes, 1915-1919 (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Northern Baptist Convention, Five Year Program, A-C, 1915-1919 (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Northern Baptist Convention, Five Year Program, D-L, 1915-1919 (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Northern Baptist Convention, Five Year Program, M, 1915-1919 (Box 20, Folder 3)
- Northern Baptist Convention, Five Year Program, N-Z, 1915-1919 (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Northern Baptist Convention/Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence A-B, 1915-1920 (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Northern Baptist Convention/Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence B-C, 1915-1920 (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Northern Baptist Convention/Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence D-J, 1915-1920 (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Northern Baptist Convention/Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence K-Q, 1915-1920 (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Northern Baptist Convention/Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence R-Z, 1915-1920 (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Federal Council of the Churches of Christ in America/League to Enforce Peace, and the Church Peace Union, 1915-1922 (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Federal Council of the Churches of Christ in America/League to Enforce Peace, and the Church Peace Union, 1915-1922 (Box 22, Folder 1)
- Federal Council of the Churches of Christ in America/League to Enforce Peace, and the Church Peace Union, 1915-1922 (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Divinity School/Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence February-August, 1916 (Box 22, Folder 3)
- Divinity School/Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence February-August, 1916 (Box 22, Folder 4)
- Divinity School, Quarter Centennial Program, 1916 (Box 22, Folder 5)
- Divinity School, University Press correspondence, January-July, 1916 (retained as sample) (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Divinity School, Purchasing Agent, University of Chicago, correspondence, January-June, 1916 (retained as sample) (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Shailer Mathews, Chicago Christian Institute, 1916 (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Divinity School/Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence 1916-1917 (Box 23, Folder 4)
- Divinity School/Shailer Mathews/General Correspondence 1916-1917 (Box 23, Folder 5)
- Northern Baptist Convention, Committee of Eleven, A-E, 1916-1917 (Box 23, Folder 6)
- Northern Baptist Convention, Committee of Eleven, F-L, 1916-1917 (Box 23, Folder 7)
- Northern Baptist Convention, Committee of Eleven, Shailer Mathews-Z, 1916-1917 (Box 23, Folder 8)
- Northern Baptist Convention, Committee of Eleven, Minutes, 1916-1917 (Box 24, Folder 1)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence A-G, 1917 (Box 24, Folder 2)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence H-Z, 1917 (Box 24, Folder 3)
- M, H. P. Judson correspondence, 1917 (Box 24, Folder 4)
- Baptist Theological Union, 1917 (Box 24, Folder 5)
- Shailer Mathews, Chicago Christian Institute. (Box 24, Folder 6)
- Divinity School, University Press, 1917 (retained as sample), Degrees, University Preachers, 1917-1918 (Box 24, Folder 7)
- Divinity School, Official notices, 1917-1918 (Box 25, Folder 1)
- War, 1917-1918 (Box 25, Folder 2)
- War, 1917-1918 (Box 25, Folder 3)
- War, 1917-1918 (Box 25, Folder 4)
- War, 1917-1918 (Box 25, Folder 5)
- War, Chaplains, 1917-1918 (Box 25, Folder 6)
- War, Red Cross, 1917-1918 (Box 25, Folder 7)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence A-L, 1918 (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence M-Z, 1918 (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Divinity School, Regulations, 1918 (Box 26, Folder 3)
- M, H. P. Judson correspondence, 1918 (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Baptist Theological Union, 1918 (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Divinity School, American Association of University Professors, 1918-1919 (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Divinity School, University Preachers, 1918-1919 (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Shailer Mathews/Chautaugua Institute, 1918-1919 (Box 27, Folder 1)
- Shailer Mathews/Chautaugua Institute, 1918-1919 (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Shailer Mathews/Chautaugua Institute, Arthur E. Bestor correspondence, 1918-1919 (Box 27, Folder 3)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence A-C, 1919 (Box 27, Folder 4)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence D-F, 1919 (Box 27, Folder 5)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence G-L, 1919 (Box 27, Folder 6)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence M-Z, 1919 (Box 28, Folder 1)
- Divinity School, Curriculum, 1919 (Box 28, Folder 2)
- Divinity School, Official notices, 1919 (Box 28, Folder 3)
- Divinity School, American Association of University Professors, 1919 (Box 28, Folder 4)
- M, H. P. Judson correspondence, 1919 (Box 28, Folder 5)
- Shailer Mathews/Personal Correspondence, 1919 (Box 28, Folder 6)
- Shailer Mathews, Macmillan Company correspondence (Box 28, Folder 7)
- Baptist Theological Union, 1919 (Box 28, Folder 8)
- Co-operative Council of City Missions of Chicago, 1919 (Box 28, Folder 9)
- Federal Council of the Churches of Christ in America/League to Enforce Peace, and the Church Peace Union, 1919 (Box 28, Folder 10)
- Northern Baptist Convention, Program, 1919 (Box 29, Folder 1)
- Northern Baptist Convention, Program, 1919 (Box 29, Folder 2)
- Northern Baptist Convention, Committee of Five, 1919 (Box 29, Folder 3)
- Divinity School, University Preachers, 1919 (Box 29, Folder 4)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence A-C, 1920 (Box 29, Folder 5)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence D-G, 1920 (Box 29, Folder 6)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence H-P, 1920 (Box 30, Folder 1)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence R-Z, 1920 (Box 30, Folder 2)
- Divinity School, Institute for Church Workers, 1920 (Box 30, Folder 3)
- Divinity School, Official notices, 1920 (Box 30, Folder 4)
- Divinity School, Theological Seminary Conference, 1920 (Box 30, Folder 5)
- M, H. P. Judson correspondence, 1920 (Box 30, Folder 6)
- Shailer Mathews/Personal Correspondence, 1920 (Box 30, Folder 7)
- Shailer Mathews, Redpath Bureau (lecturing), 1920 (Box 30, Folder 8)
- Baptist Executive Council of Chicago, 1920 (Box 30, Folder 9)
- Chicago Church Federation, 1920 (Box 31, Folder 1)
- Co-operative Council of City Missions of Chicago, 1920 (Box 31, Folder 2)
- Northern Baptist Convention, Board of Promotion, 1920 (Box 31, Folder 3)
- Divinity School, University Preachers, 1920-1921 (Box 31, Folder 4)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence A-C, 1921 (Box 31, Folder 5)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence D-M, 1921 (Box 31, Folder 6)
- Divinity School/General Correspondence N-Z, 1921 (Box 31, Folder 7)
- Divinity School, Official notices, 1921 (Box 32, Folder 1)
- M, H. P. Judson correspondence, 1921 (Box 32, Folder 2)
- Shailer Mathews/Chautaugua Institute, 1921 (Box 32, Folder 3)
- Shailer Mathews, Engagements, A-G, 1921 (retained as sample) (Box 32, Folder 4)